<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>BhandLab</title><link>https://ankibues.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on BhandLab</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 14 Jan 2022 23:49:25 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ankibues.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Publications</title><link>https://ankibues.github.io/publications/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Dec 2022 11:22:43 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://ankibues.github.io/publications/</guid><description>Journal articles: Link to heading Bhandari, A., &amp;amp; Jiang, D. (2021). A multiscale numerical modeling investigation on the significance of flow partitioning for the development of quartz c‐axis fabrics. Journal of Geophysical Research: Solid Earth, 126, e2020JB021040 Jiang, D., &amp;amp; Bhandari, A. (2018). Pressure variations among rheologically heterogeneous elements in Earth’s lithosphere: A micromechanics investigation. Earth and Planetary Science Letters 498, 397- 407
Saha, L., Frei, D., Gerdes, A., Pati, J.</description></item><item><title>You are the Universe!</title><link>https://ankibues.github.io/posts/blog2/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Jan 2022 23:49:25 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://ankibues.github.io/posts/blog2/</guid><description>Very often during our casual chats, my friend and I come across this conversation. She asks me, “Who do you think you are, mister?”, and I jokingly reply to her, “I am the Universe!”. And we laugh it away.
But, there seems to be a certain truth about that statement. From a perspective, I am the Universe. And so are You.
Our scientific understanding of the universe tells us the story of how the big bang created this spacetime continuum, which seems to be billions of years old.</description></item><item><title>How Emotional Are You?</title><link>https://ankibues.github.io/posts/blog1/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Jan 2022 23:49:25 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://ankibues.github.io/posts/blog1/</guid><description>How Emotional Are You?
To answer this question, let’s play a quick game: As you read this line, close your eyes for 10 seconds and think of the names of all kinds of emotions you have ever felt . For example, ‘anger’ and ‘joy’ are two such emotions. Try out this activity. Think of all the emotion concept names you can think of.
Don’t scroll down till you have thought of the answer!</description></item><item><title>Welcome to the BhandLab!</title><link>https://ankibues.github.io/posts/welcome/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 23:49:25 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://ankibues.github.io/posts/welcome/</guid><description>I decided to give myself a new year gift of a personal website, a digital place where I can share my ideas, learnings, lessons, innovations, art, music and whatever there is to offer. After a whole lot of procrastinating, I decided to try out the new website in Hugo. Starting with a pretty simple theme , I intend to modify it to create something of my own.
This is a digital place of freedom and I will talk about everything I can: geology, math, guitar, philosophy, writing or tech stuff.</description></item><item><title>About</title><link>https://ankibues.github.io/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Dec 2020 11:26:13 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://ankibues.github.io/about/</guid><description>With more than four years experience in scientific computing followed by more than a year&amp;rsquo;s industrial experience in tech industry, I manage compliance projects and lead the Quality Assurance Team at YuJa helping build leading technology solutions for higher education enterprises.
I come from Lucknow, India, where I spent most of my childhood. I completed my undergraduate in 2016 from Indian Institute of Technology Roorkee, majoring in Geological Technology. I moved to Canada in 2016 for my PhD program at Western University.</description></item><item><title>Projects</title><link>https://ankibues.github.io/projects/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Dec 2020 11:24:32 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://ankibues.github.io/projects/</guid><description>Scientific Computing: Link to heading 1. Simulating pressure variation in Earth&amp;rsquo;s heterogeneous rocks Link to heading Pressure in a rock element in Earth&amp;rsquo;s lithosphere may vary from its ambient value and if significant, may influence the physical processes. This poses major problems in routine use of pressure as a proxy for depth in geodynamic models. This project developed and applied physics-based numerical models to simulate pressure deviation in a rheologically distinct rock element in an ambient rock medium of a non-linear viscous anisotropic rheology.</description></item><item><title>Contact</title><link>https://ankibues.github.io/contact/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ankibues.github.io/contact/</guid><description>Feel free to follow me on Twitter
check out my writing on Medium
follow my projects or colloborate with me on GitHub, or
connect via email.
Cheers!</description></item></channel></rss>