<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Ankit Bhandari</title><link>https://ankibues.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on Ankit Bhandari</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 Dec 2022 11:22:43 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ankibues.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Publications</title><link>https://ankibues.github.io/publications/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Dec 2022 11:22:43 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://ankibues.github.io/publications/</guid><description>Medium Stories: Link to heading What Happens When You Think In Terms of Entropy? A Perspective On Entropy And Life
How Rocks Flow Beneath Your Feet? Using Computer Simulation to see what happens 30 kilometers below your feet
What’s Your Emotional Granularity? Understanding your emotions and well-being
You Are The Universe. A Perspective Shift
5 Steps To Understand The World Using Mental Models. All Models Are Wrong, But Some Are Useful.</description></item><item><title>You are the Universe!</title><link>https://ankibues.github.io/posts/blog2/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Jan 2022 23:49:25 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://ankibues.github.io/posts/blog2/</guid><description>Very often during our casual chats, my friend and I come across this conversation. She asks me, “Who do you think you are, mister?”, and I jokingly reply to her, “I am the Universe!”. And we laugh it away.
But, there seems to be a certain truth about that statement. From a perspective, I am the Universe. And so are You.
Our scientific understanding of the universe tells us the story of how the big bang created this spacetime continuum, which seems to be billions of years old.</description></item><item><title>How Emotional Are You?</title><link>https://ankibues.github.io/posts/blog1/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Jan 2022 23:49:25 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://ankibues.github.io/posts/blog1/</guid><description>How Emotional Are You?
To answer this question, let’s play a quick game: As you read this line, close your eyes for 10 seconds and think of the names of all kinds of emotions you have ever felt . For example, ‘anger’ and ‘joy’ are two such emotions. Try out this activity. Think of all the emotion concept names you can think of.
Don’t scroll down till you have thought of the answer!</description></item><item><title>Welcome to the BhandLab!</title><link>https://ankibues.github.io/posts/welcome/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 23:49:25 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://ankibues.github.io/posts/welcome/</guid><description>I decided to give myself a new year gift of a personal website, a digital place where I can share my ideas, learnings, lessons, innovations, art, music and whatever there is to offer. After a whole lot of procrastinating, I decided to try out the new website in Hugo. Starting with a pretty simple theme , I intend to modify it to create something of my own.
This is a digital place of freedom and I will talk about everything I can: geology, math, guitar, philosophy, writing or tech stuff.</description></item><item><title>About</title><link>https://ankibues.github.io/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ankibues.github.io/about/</guid><description>With over 4 years of experience in research and teaching followed by 2 years in educational technology industry, Ankit builds educational technology at BhandLab. In addition, he provides tech consultancy to businesses for relevant technical problems.
With background in both academic teaching and employee training, he is passionate about creating novel learning experiences using technology.
He comes from Lucknow, India, where he spent most of his childhood. After completing his undergraduate degree in Engineering from Indian Institute of Technology Roorkee, he moved to Canada in 2016 for his PhD program at Western University.</description></item><item><title>Compliance</title><link>https://ankibues.github.io/projects/Compliance/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ankibues.github.io/projects/Compliance/</guid><description>Compliance Link to heading While working in the Educational Technology (Ed-Tech) industry, Ankit managed many compliance projects. Compliance means making sure that the software and software development practices are in accordance to relevant industry standards of accessibility, security, and interoperability, etc.
Ankit believes that compliance is a great strategy for building a great product that leads to greater customer satisfaction!
Below are some Compliance Certifications Ankit has managed during his tenure at YuJa:</description></item><item><title>Contact</title><link>https://ankibues.github.io/contact/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ankibues.github.io/contact/</guid><description>Follow him on Twitter
Check out his writing on Medium
Follow his projects or collaborate on GitHub, or
Connect via email.
Cheers!</description></item><item><title>Projects</title><link>https://ankibues.github.io/projects/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ankibues.github.io/projects/</guid><description> Software Development Link to heading Compliance Link to heading Test Automation Link to heading Scientific Research Link to heading</description></item><item><title>Scientific Research</title><link>https://ankibues.github.io/projects/ScientificResearch/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ankibues.github.io/projects/ScientificResearch/</guid><description>Scientific Research Projects Link to heading Pressure variation in Earth&amp;rsquo;s heterogeneous rocks Link to heading Pressure in a rock element in Earth&amp;rsquo;s lithosphere may vary from its ambient value and if significant, may influence the physical processes. This poses major problems in routine use of pressure as a proxy for depth in geodynamic models. Ankit developed and applied physics-based numerical models to simulate pressure deviation in a rheologically distinct rock element in an ambient rock medium of a non-linear viscous anisotropic rheology.</description></item><item><title>Software Development</title><link>https://ankibues.github.io/projects/SoftwareDevelopment/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ankibues.github.io/projects/SoftwareDevelopment/</guid><description>Software Development Link to heading QuestEd: Link to heading QuestEd is an open-source educational technology platform enabling instructors to craft story-driven, gamified learning experiences with Artificial Intelligence (AI).
Instructors can create interactive gamified learning experience by adding keywords or even a lesson plan (in the form of pdf, or document file). Using generative AI, QuestEd develops a story-based learning experience called Quest, that can be accessed by a learner.</description></item><item><title>Test Automation</title><link>https://ankibues.github.io/projects/Test%20Automation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ankibues.github.io/projects/Test%20Automation/</guid><description>Test Automation Link to heading Ankit worked as a Quality Assurance Engineer at YuJa. With manual testing of software and hardware application already in practice, he led the automation development to meet the growing needs of testing at YuJa. This involved developing automated test cases for YuJa EVP, which is a web-based platform that enables educational institutions to store, manage, distribute and stream media content. This project utilized Selenium based TestNg framework in Java for automating the test scenarios such as uploading video/audio files, perrform certain types of actions on media files, creating different types of users, etc.</description></item></channel></rss>