<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Ankit Bhandari</title><link>https://ankibues.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on Ankit Bhandari</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 Dec 2022 11:22:43 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ankibues.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Publications</title><link>https://ankibues.github.io/publications/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Dec 2022 11:22:43 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://ankibues.github.io/publications/</guid><description>Medium Stories: Link to heading What Happens When You Think In Terms of Entropy? A Perspective On Entropy And Life
How Rocks Flow Beneath Your Feet? Using Computer Simulation to see what happens 30 kilometers below your feet
What’s Your Emotional Granularity? Understanding your emotions and well-being
You Are The Universe. A Perspective Shift
5 Steps To Understand The World Using Mental Models. All Models Are Wrong, But Some Are Useful.</description></item><item><title>You are the Universe!</title><link>https://ankibues.github.io/posts/blog2/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Jan 2022 23:49:25 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://ankibues.github.io/posts/blog2/</guid><description>Very often during our casual chats, my friend and I come across this conversation. She asks me, “Who do you think you are, mister?”, and I jokingly reply to her, “I am the Universe!”. And we laugh it away.
But, there seems to be a certain truth about that statement. From a perspective, I am the Universe. And so are You.
Our scientific understanding of the universe tells us the story of how the big bang created this spacetime continuum, which seems to be billions of years old.</description></item><item><title>How Emotional Are You?</title><link>https://ankibues.github.io/posts/blog1/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Jan 2022 23:49:25 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://ankibues.github.io/posts/blog1/</guid><description>How Emotional Are You?
To answer this question, let’s play a quick game: As you read this line, close your eyes for 10 seconds and think of the names of all kinds of emotions you have ever felt . For example, ‘anger’ and ‘joy’ are two such emotions. Try out this activity. Think of all the emotion concept names you can think of.
Don’t scroll down till you have thought of the answer!</description></item><item><title>Welcome to the BhandLab!</title><link>https://ankibues.github.io/posts/welcome/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 23:49:25 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://ankibues.github.io/posts/welcome/</guid><description>I decided to give myself a new year gift of a personal website, a digital place where I can share my ideas, learnings, lessons, innovations, art, music and whatever there is to offer. After a whole lot of procrastinating, I decided to try out the new website in Hugo. Starting with a pretty simple theme , I intend to modify it to create something of my own.
This is a digital place of freedom and I will talk about everything I can: geology, math, guitar, philosophy, writing or tech stuff.</description></item><item><title>About</title><link>https://ankibues.github.io/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ankibues.github.io/about/</guid><description>With over 4 years of experience in academic research, teaching and scientific computing followed by 2 years in educational technology industry, Ankit builds educational software at BhandLab and provides consultancy to businesses for relevant technical problems.
With background in both academic teaching and employee training, he is passionate about creating novel learning experiences using technology.
He comes from Lucknow, India, where he spent most of his childhood. After completing his undergraduate degree in Engineering from Indian Institute of Technology Roorkee, he moved to Canada in 2016 for his PhD program at Western University.</description></item><item><title>Contact</title><link>https://ankibues.github.io/contact/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ankibues.github.io/contact/</guid><description>Follow him on Twitter
Check out his writing on Medium
Follow his projects or collaborate on GitHub, or
Connect via email.
Cheers!</description></item><item><title>Projects</title><link>https://ankibues.github.io/projects/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ankibues.github.io/projects/</guid><description>Software Development Link to heading Ankit is currently working on a few software products that are scheduled to be launched in 2024. Follow BhandLab for upcoming updates!
Compliance Link to heading While working in the Educational Technology (Ed-Tech) industry, Ankit managed many compliance projects. Compliance means making sure that the software and software development practices are in accordance to relevant industry standards of accessibility, security, and interoperability, etc.
Ankit believes that compliance is a great strategy for building a great product that leads to greater customer satisfaction!</description></item></channel></rss>