<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on BhandLab</title><link>http://bhandlab.github.io/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on BhandLab</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 14 Jan 2022 23:49:25 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://bhandlab.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>You are the Universe!</title><link>http://bhandlab.github.io/posts/blog2/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Jan 2022 23:49:25 +0530</pubDate><guid>http://bhandlab.github.io/posts/blog2/</guid><description>Very often during our casual chats, my friend and I come across this conversation. She asks me, “Who do you think you are, mister?”, and I jokingly reply to her, “I am the Universe!”. And we laugh it away.
But, there seems to be a certain truth about that statement. From a perspective, I am the Universe. And so are You.
Our scientific understanding of the universe tells us the story of how the big bang created this spacetime continuum, which seems to be billions of years old.</description></item><item><title>How Emotional Are You?</title><link>http://bhandlab.github.io/posts/blog1/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Jan 2022 23:49:25 +0530</pubDate><guid>http://bhandlab.github.io/posts/blog1/</guid><description>How Emotional Are You?
To answer this question, let’s play a quick game: As you read this line, close your eyes for 10 seconds and think of the names of all kinds of emotions you have ever felt . For example, ‘anger’ and ‘joy’ are two such emotions. Try out this activity. Think of all the emotion concept names you can think of.
Don’t scroll down till you have thought of the answer!</description></item><item><title>Welcome to the BhandLab!</title><link>http://bhandlab.github.io/posts/welcome/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 23:49:25 +0530</pubDate><guid>http://bhandlab.github.io/posts/welcome/</guid><description>I decided to give myself a new year gift of a personal website, a digital place where I can share my ideas, learnings, lessons, innovations, art, music and whatever there is to offer. After a whole lot of procrastinating, I decided to try out the new website in Hugo. Starting with a pretty simple theme , I intend to modify it to create something of my own.
This is a digital place of freedom and I will talk about everything I can: geology, math, guitar, philosophy, writing or tech stuff.</description></item></channel></rss>